Aveontae M. Frazier

7501 W 61st Apt 133 - Mission, KS 66202. - (860) 879-1451 - amfrazier01@gmail.com

SUMMARY

INFORMATION SYSTEMS AND CODING BOOTCAMP STUDENT WITH EXPERIENCE AND EXTENSIVE EDUCATION IN SOFTWARE DESIGN AND APPLICATION DEVELOPMENT. STRONG WORK ETHIC IN TEAM OR INDIVIDUAL SETTINGS TO DRIVE PRODUCT SUCCESS AND PROCESS EFFICIENCY. STRONG TROUBLESHOOTING AND PROBLEM-SOLVING SKILLS WITH AN ANALYTICAL MINDSET.

KNOWLEDGE, SKILLS, AND ABILITIES

- KNOWLEDGE OF FUNDAMENTAL CONCEPTS OF WEB DEVELOPMENT, INCLUDING HTML, CSS, AND JAVASCRIPT.
- ADDITIONAL ACADEMIC EXPERIENCE WITH PYTHON AND MATHLAB PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES
- ABILITY TO BUILD A CLIENT-SIDE APPLICATION USING THIRD-PARTY API'S.
- KNOWLEDGEABLE IN TROUBLESHOOTING BASIC SOFTWARE ISSUES.
- ABILITY TO WORK WITH SERVERS, DATABASES, AND OTHER BACK-END TECHNOLOGIES, SUCH AS MYSQL DATABASE, NODE.JS, AND MORE.
- SKILLED IN TROUBLESHOOTING CODE RELATED ISSUES/DEFECTS.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF KANSAS 03/2023 – PRESENT

CODING BOOT CAMP CERTIFICATE

EXPECTED COMPLETION DATE: SEPTEMBER 2023

LAWERENCE, KS

UNIVERSITY OF KANSAS 08/2022 – PRESENT

LAWERENCE, KS

OVERLAND PARK, KS

12/2017 - 06/2020

EAST GRANBY, CT

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE
INFORMATION SYSTEMS
EXPECTED GRADUATION DATE: DECEMBER 2023

GPA: 3.93

JOHNSON COUNTY COMMUNITY COLLEGE COMPLETION DATE: 06/2022

ASSOCIATE OF SCIENCE

GENERAL SCIENCES GPA: 3.5

UNITED STATES AIR FORCE ACADEMY 08/2020 - 12/2021

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE COLORADO SPRINGS, CO

FOREIGN AREA STUDIES & POLITICAL SCIENCE WITH A MINOR IN PORTUGUESE GPA: $3.0\,$

UNIVERSITY OF CONNECTICUT 01/2019 - 05/2020

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE

CIVIL ENGINEERING

GPA: 3.5

MILITARY EXPERIENCE

UNITED STATES AIR FORCE 12/2017 – 02/2022

AFSC-3E651

• Honorably discharged on February 16, 2022

CONNECTICUT AIR NATIONAL GUARD OPERATIONS MANAGER, CIVIL ENGINEERING SQUADRON

• Established and managed the operation of the command and control center

- Prepared and managed work requirements during approval, processing, and completion stages of work
- Monitored work costs up to \$10,000 for personal approval to ensure compliance with Air Force limits
- Developed and established operation and maintenance procedures to ensure maximum efficiency
- Reviewed all Air Force Instruction to ensure our office's compliance with the regulations

WORK EXPERIENCE

T-MOBILE 05/2022 - 03/2023

HOME INTERNET EXPERT/TELESALES

HOURS WORKED PER WEEK: 37

- · Served existing and prospective customers, while providing a best-in-class customer experience and building loyalty
- Consistently leveraged digital tools in interactions and onboarding
- · Completed training on T-Mobile virtual retail experience, new skills, and processes, knowledge of systems and reference resources
- Consistently sought out information between customers, while also learning about innovations in wireless and technology
- Completed daily sales meetings to set goals and review any new strategic moves made by the organization

UCONN FACILITY OPERATIONS

03/2019 - 06/2020

OVERLAND PARK, KS

STORRS, CT

CALL CENTER STUDENT STAFF HOURS WORKED PER WEEK: 20

- Managed the operations of all UConn facilities 600+ and building services
- · Coordinated with customers, managers, and technicians in case of miscommunication and/or follow-up work
- Processed 20-40 work orders a day to fix/improve facilities

INTERNSHIP EXPERIENCE

PRUDENTIAL FINANCIAL INC.

07/2019 - 08/2019 *HARTFORD, CT*

SUMMER FINANCE INTERN, EXPENSE PLANNING&ANALYSIS TEAM HOURS WORKED PER WEEK: 35

- Searched and pulled quarterly detailed expense reports that were composed of over \$900 million of expenses
- Identified difference in thousands/millions in 2018 actual expenses vs present 6-month actuals and differences in 2nd quarter forecast as opposed to the full-year plan
- Updated PowerPoints used for clients for end-of-the-quarter reporting or forecasting

SKILLS

JOB-RELATED SKILLS

- MICROSOFT OFFICE, TEAMWORK
- COMMUNICATION
- ANALYTICAL SKILLS
- SALES

LICENSES

• PRIVATE PILOT LICENSE

COMMUNITY INVOLVEMENT

•	UNITED STATES AIR FORCE ACADEMY PREP SCHOOL EPW PROGRAM CONTRIBUTOR	2020 - 2021
•	CHARLIE SQ. ACADEMIC OFFICER	2021 - 2021
•	NUTMEG BIG BROTHERS BIG SISTERS PROGRAM	2019 - 2020
•	UNITED STATES NAVAL SEA CADET CORPS	2016 - 2018
•	NHS PEER MENTORING PROGRAM	2016 - 2018

LEADERSHIP/AWARDS

- UNITED STATES AIR FORCE ACADEMY CONGRESSIONAL NOMINEE
- OPERATIONS MANAGEMENT APPRENTICESHIP SUPERIOR PERFORMER
- AIR FORCE BASIC MILITARY TRAINING HONOR GRADUATE
- EARLY PATH TO WINGS SCHOLARSHIP RECIPIENT/GRADUATE
- NEWINGTON HIGH SCHOOL BUSINESS ACADEMY STUDENT AWARD 2018